<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code on Hooked on Data</title>
    <link>/tags/code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code on Hooked on Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Going off the map: An overview of some other purrr functions</title>
      <link>/going-off-the-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/going-off-the-map/</guid>
      <description>I recently completed Colin Fay’s excellent DataCamp course, Intermediate Functional Programming with purrr (full disclosure: I work at DataCamp, but part of why I joined was that I was a big fan of the short, interactive course format). Although I’ve used purrr before, there were a lot of functions in this course that were new to me.
If you’re familiar with purrr, it’s probably because of the map() functions. And if you’ve been a little bit intimidated, I’m right there with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lesser Known Stars of the Tidyverse</title>
      <link>/the-lesser-known-stars-of-the-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-lesser-known-stars-of-the-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>In early 2018, I gave a few conference talks on “The Lesser Known Stars of the Tidyverse.” I focused on some packages and functions that aren’t as well known as the core parts of ggplot2 and dplyr but are very helpful in exploratory analysis. I walked through an example analysis of Kaggle’s 2017 State of Data Science and Machine Learning Survey to show how I would use these functions in an exploratory analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making R Code Faster: A Case Study</title>
      <link>/making-r-code-faster-a-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/making-r-code-faster-a-case-study/</guid>
      <description>About two months ago I put a call out to Rstats twitter:
#rstats twitter - who loves helping to make (short) code run as fast as possible? Playing w/ foreach, doparallel, data.table but know little — Emily Robinson (@robinson_es) October 4, 2017   I had a working, short script that took 3 1/2 minutes to run. While this may be fine if you only need to run it once, I needed to run it hundreds of time for simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>